快一點啦 今天大日子耶
Hurry up, it's a big day.
你想讓新娘子等你一個人喔
You don't want to make the bride wait for you, do you?
老闆 一樣
The usual, boss.
錢一樣跟我媽算
Put it on my mom's tab.
好 ok
All right, no problem
1994年
那一年 我十六歲
I was 16 that year
張雨生的歌聲還在
Chang Yu-Sheng's voice was still heard on TV shows.
張學友的「吻別」大賣了一百多萬張卡帶
Jacky Cheung sold more than one million cassettes for the "KissGoodbye" album.
組頭還沒開始看中華職棒
The bookies hadn't started watching CPBL
經典的龍象大戰總是滿場
and the classic Dragon-Elephant games were always sold out.
那年
That year
有一個皮膚黑黑的女生五度五關(張惠妹)
a girl with tanned skin won the championship on the local talent show
贏得了五燈獎的冠軍
for five consecutive rounds.
那一年…
That year...
那些年
Those years.
我叫柯景騰
My name is Ko Ching-Teng.
同學都叫我柯騰
My friends called me Ko-Teng
我國中念的是彰化市精誠中學
I went to Jingcheng in Changhua City for junior high school.
高中念的也是精誠中學
As for high school, I stuck to the same one, too.
這是許博淳
This is Hsu Bo-Chun.
從國中起就是我最好的朋友
He has been my best friend since junior high school.
許博淳隨時隨地都在勃起
He's always getting a boner
所以外號叫「勃起」
that's why we named him "Boner".
幹
Fuck!
幹三小
Fuck what?
死柯騰 別跑
You are dead meat. Don't run.
這是阿和
This is A-Ho.
我們從國小就一直同班到高中
We have been in the same class all the way from elementary to high school.
每一個故事都有一個胖子
There is a fat guy in every story.
阿和就是那一個胖子
A-Ho is the fat guy in our story.
你們很煩耶
Stop bugging me.
剛剛好啦
Why not?
教官早
Good morning, Sir.
早
Good morning.
教官早
Good morning, Sir.
早
Good morning.
教官早
Good morning, Sir.
早
Good morning.
教官早
Good morning, Sir.
頭髮太長囉
Your hair is too long.
該剪的要剪一剪了
It's time to get a haircut.
你不要每天都這樣好不好
Gosh, can you stop that?
怎樣
What?
不要每次都從後面嚇人啊
Stop doing that
跟你講幾次了
I have told you a million times!
所以咧
Why not?
很浪費啊
You totally wasted my food
我熱狗只吃一口
I only had one bite of that hotdog.
所以
So...
啊你是不會接喔
Don't you know how to catch?
曹雞巴
Cock Tsao.
一大早就那麼雞巴
Why are you such a jackass in the morning.
我跟你說
You know what?
昨天我抽到Grant Hill 1:40的限定卡
I won a Grant Hill 1 to 40 limited edition card yesterday.
這是老曹
This is Tsao.
老曹從國中跟我同班就是一個很雞巴的人
We have been classmates ever since junior high and he has always been an ass.
所以有時候我會叫老曹
We called him.
(Cock, Cocky, Dumbass Tsao or "Tsao motherfucker")
這麼雞巴
Show off?
不然你拿你1:100的Penny Hardaway來換
We can switch then for your 1 to 100 Penny Hardaway cards.
我才不要咧
No way!
不要 不要還來
Piss off, then.
我這幾個好朋友唯一的共通點
The only thing that these boys shared in common with...
就是喜歡班上最乖的好學生
was that they all had a crush on the honor student in the class.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
在我看起來
From my point of view.
沈佳宜只是比一般的女生還要再漂亮一點點而已
Shen Chia-Yi was only slightly prettier than the other girls.
真搞不懂
Don't know what the guys were thinking.
欸 沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
幹嘛
Yes?
妳昨天有看玫瑰之夜嗎
Did you watch Rose Night yesterday?
妳說那個太極峽谷的那個照片啊
Are you talking about the Taichi Gorge photo?
對呀 我覺得超可怕的
Yeah, the picture was horrifying
而且我全身都起雞皮疙瘩了
I got goose bumps all over.
那個故事聽起來很可怕
The story sounds terrifying but...
可是那張照片我看不太出來耶
I can't really tell from the picture though
我覺得只是拍攝角度的問題
I think it was the shooting angle that does the trick.
真的嗎
You think so?
第五課跟第六課的考卷
Now, start doing the exercises for lesson five and six.
寫不完的升旗後繼續寫
Continue after the assembly if you can't finish.
自己寫自己的
Focus on your own exercises.
不可以討論
No discussion.
這是廖英宏
This is Liao Ying-Hung.
廖這個姓
His surname, Liao, is a verb in Chinese.
是個動詞
And it means to scratch.
既然是個動詞
Since it's a verb
就不能白白浪費
we should make good use of this verb.
所以我們幫他取了個綽號
Thus, we gave him a nickname.
叫「廖該邊」
"Groin" (Scratching Groin)
該邊當然也喜歡沈佳宜
"Groin" likes Shen Chia-Yi, too.
因為該邊喜歡班上每一個女生
That's because he likes every girl in the class.
一大清早就這麼
It's early morning and everyone looks half asleep.
沒 精 神
Stand straight.
還睡
Wake up!
站好
Stand straight.
還動
Stop moving.
起立
Stand up.
立正
Attention.
敬禮
Salute.
老師好
Good morning, Miss Chou.
各位同學好 坐下
Good morning, everyone. Sit down.
乾隆丁亥年
In year 1974, it was still the Qing dynasty.
也就在
So it means that.
丁亥年就在我們乾隆的三十二年
It was the thirty second year that China was ruled under Emperor Qianlong.
其實高中跟國中差不了多少
There was really not that much difference between junior high and senior high.
地獄十七層跟十六層的差別而已
Just a matter of how deep you are in hell.
唸書 考試 整個很無聊
Endless studies, exams... it's all very boring!
有人物時間 還有再來就是地點
There is the character, the time and then it's the place.
那地點是在哪裡呢
Where is the place?
地點就在我們的上元之…
The place...
但想辦法找一點事做就不會那麼無聊了
But, we can always find a way to entertain ourselves!
許博淳
Hsu Bo-Chun
起來念下一段
stand up and read the next section.
站起來念啊
Stand up and read.
上到哪一段都不知道
You don't even know where we are.
有沒有在上課啊
Hello... are you in the classroom.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng
你在笑什麼
what are you laughing at?
你念
You read it.
汝以一念之貞 遇人仳離
(Reading paragraphs from the textbook)
站起來念
Stand up and read.
不是很方便
It's not very convenient.
什麼叫做「不是很方便」
What do you mean "not very convenient"?
站起來
Stand up.
上課打手槍
Jerking off.
Jerking off right in the class
我教書教這麼多年
I have been a teacher for so many years
考試作弊的
I have seen students who cheat
打架的
get into fights
勒索同學的
black mail.
甚至於想打老師的
Or even those who beat up teachers!
什麼壞學生我沒見過
I have seen all kinds of problematic students
我就沒見過像你們這樣變態的
but just no perverts like you!
又沒有射
I didn't even ejaculate.
你還說
And that's an excuse?
對呀
Yeah.
我們只是打好…
We were just fooling around...
你也一樣
You, too.
你們父母花這麼多錢把你們送到學校來讀書
Your parents spent so much money to send you to school
你們不知道好好珍惜
and you guys don't even cherish how lucky you are.
什麼是打手槍啊
What's jerk off?
上課打手槍
Jerking off in the classroom.
喂
Hey?
我不知道耶
I don't know.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi
你出來一下
come out here for a second.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi
柯景騰以後坐在你前面
from now on, Ko Ching-Teng will sit in front of you.
你幫老師好好管管他
Keep an eye on him for me.
千萬不要讓他把其他同學帶壞
Don't let him be a bad influence on others.
順便督促一下他功課
Give him a push on his schoolwork, as well.
知不知道
Okay?
許博淳
Hsu Bo-Chun.
以後
In the future
你坐在謝明和前面
you will sit in front of Hsieh Ming-Ho.
一樣
The same goes for you.
不要給我作怪
Don't goof around again.
再作怪的話 我請你父母到學校來
If you do, I will ask your parents to come to school.
聽到沒有
Get it?
聽到
Got it.
都上課去
Now, go to your class.
謝謝老師
Thank you, sir.
雖然沈佳宜國中已經跟我同班了三年
Even though Shen Chia-Yi and I have been in the same class ever since junior high
但好學生跟壞學生之間的距離
the distance between an honor student and a bad student
並沒有因此有任何的改變
always stayed the same.
換到這種鳥地方 倒霉啊倒霉啊
It's shitty luck to sit in such a shitty seat.
到底是誰倒霉啊
Who has bad luck now?
坐在我前面
You are sitting in front of me now.
你不要再搞一些幼稚的把戲
You better stop your childish pranks.
造成我的困擾
So you don't bring me unnecessary troubles.
當好學生真好
It must be nice to be an honor student.
只要成績好
Just because you have good marks
就能亂嗆人
doesn't mean you can boss people around.
誰稀罕管你啊
Who cares about what you think?
欸 你也不用太管他啦
Don't mind him, don't let him bother you.
對呀
That's right.
他只是上課愛打手槍而已啦
He just likes to masturbate in the classroom.
幹
Fuck.
你會喜歡作怪 就是因為你平常不好好唸書的關係
The reason you like to goof around is because you don't concentrate on your studies.
對啊
Yeah.
你好強喔 你好會讀書喔
You're so clever, you are such a smart ass.
像沈佳宜這種好學生
A nerd like Shen Chia-Yi
逮到機會 就喜歡多管閒事
likes to poke her nose into other people's business whenever she gets a chance.
整天畫這種智障的東西
All you do is drawing these retarded figures every day.
沒前途啦
Where's the future in that?
要你管啊
It's none of your business
是沒有要管啊 只是想笑一下而已呀
I'm pretty much minding my own business. I just want to have a good laugh.
沒品
Moron.
為什麼你畫的智障 每個都是光頭啊
How come every retard you drew is bald?
你是歧視光頭 還是歧視智障
Do you discriminate against bald heads or retards?
管好你自己就好
Mind your own business.
你烏龜喔
Man, you are as slow as a turtle!
拜拜
Bye.
柯騰
Ko-Teng.
啊
What?
你不要一直為難沈佳宜
Stop giving Shen Chia-Yi a hard time.
媽啦
Yeah right.
就這樣
That's all.
還這樣咧
That's all???
每個男人都想要成為最強的男人
Every man wants to be the strongest man.
我也不例外
Including me.
總有一天
One day
我一定要成為跟師父一樣強的男人
I will be as strong as my master.
你 已 經 死 了
You are D.E.A.D.
我的個性之所以這麼豪邁 跟我的家人大有關係
The fact that I am so reckless has got something to do with my family.
媽 洗髮精沒了
Ma, shampoo is out.
唉唷 穿衣服啦
Hey, put some clothes on.
都這麼大了
You're a grown-up now
真的很大吼
I know, it has grown so big, right?
我老爸在家裡 也是脫褲懶
My father also likes to walk around butt naked in the house.
今天學校有打電話來
The school called today.
男女合校就男女合校
What's the big deal about coed school?
在學校就專心讀書
Concentrate at school.
不要搞一些有的沒的嘛
Stop goofing around.
搞什麼
What did I do?
趁熱吃 趁熱吃
Eat first, while it's still hot.
吃完再說啦
Talk later.
你成績一直都吊車尾 是不是都不讀書
Why are your grades always in the bottom percentile?
整天只想搞一些談情說愛的事
Is it because you are thinking about girls all the time, is that why?
我對女生沒興趣啦
No, I am not interested in girls!
我對男生也沒興趣啊
I'm not interested in guys, either.
說到談情說愛
Speaking of girls.
我那些好朋友
Each one of my good friend
每個人喜歡沈佳宜的方式都不一樣
liked Shen Chia-Yi in a different way.
廖該邊 你想幹嘛
Groin, what are you doing?
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi
我剛剛發明了一個新魔術
I have just invented a new magic trick
第一個變給你看
I want you to be the first one to see it.
胡家瑋你 要不要順便也看一下
Hu Chia-Wei, do you want to see it, too.
搞笑的嗎
Is it a prank?
哪是啊 是很厲害的
No way. It's amazing.
看清楚喔
Look closely.
該邊的方法基本上沒錯
Basically, Groin was on the right track.
就是逗女孩子開心
It's to cheer the girls up and make them laugh.
這隻手也沒有
Nothing in this hand, either.
看清楚喔
Look closely.
廖該邊 你很無聊
Groin, you are such a bore.
比起該邊的弱智魔術
Besides Groin's retarded magic.
老曹討女生開心的方式…
Tsao had a very different way to make girls happy.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
曹國勝
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
沒人理解
And no one gets it.
阿和很喜歡看一些大人在看的雜誌
A-Ho liked to read what grown-ups read.
對很多我不想懂的事都非常瞭解
So he knew many things that we didn't.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
你記不記得我之前有借你一張Air Supply的專輯
Do you remember the Air Supply album that I lent you.
嗯
Um... I remember.
下個月他們要來開演唱會
They are coming next month.
如果我拿到票要不要一起去
Do you want to go if I have tickets?
去台北看嗎
To Taipei?
坐火車去啊
We can take the train.
胡家瑋
Hu Chia-Wei.
要不要一起去
Do you want to go with us?
好啊…
Yes, sure.
聽起來很有趣耶
Sounds fun.
用大人的方式追沈佳宜最不著痕跡
The adult's way is the most subtle way to chase after Shen Chia-Yi.
Air Supply是誰啊
Who is Air Supply?
有人說
Someone said.
展現自己最笨拙的一面也是追求女孩的一種方式
Showing one's clumsy side is also another way to pursuit girls
我想
I think.
勃起充分驗證了這個方式…
Boner has tried this many times.
許博淳
Hsu Bo-Chun.
你可不可以不要再吹了啊
Can you stop playing?
並不管用
And it proves that his way doesn't work at all.
我也有喜歡的女生
Me? Yes, there's also a girl I like.
只是我們之間 暫時不可能
But it's unlikely that we can develop anything at that point in time.
沒關係
That's fine
我會慢慢長大
I will grow up.
成為一個配得上她的男人
One clay, I will turn to be the man that deserves her.
那一天
That day.
英文老師不曉得是股票輸錢
Nobody knew if the English teacher had lost money in the stock market
還是月經亂掉
or her menstruation period went wild.
整張臉跟大便一樣臭
She had a shitty face.
散發出比平常更重的殺氣
She looked like she was about to kill someone.
起立
Stand up.
坐下 上課
Sit down. Let's begin
原本我以為
I thought
如果有一天能夠看到品學兼優的沈佳宜出糗
it would be great fun to see the smart ass student, Shen Chia-Yi
一定是上學最大的樂趣
makes a blunder
我是說
I meant.
原本
"I thought."
沒帶課本的站起來
Stand up if you didn't bring your textbook.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng
學期已經過了三分之一了
we have gone through a third of this semester.
每天要用的英文課本你都沒帶
And you don't even have your English textbook with you, which we use every day.
你有沒有心上課啊
Are you serious about getting an education?
椅子
Chair.
你知道私立學校的學費很貴嗎
Don't you know private schools are expensive?
連最基本的課本都不帶
If you don't even have your textbook
你來學校幹嘛
then why do you even bother coming to school?
來吃便當啊
Here to eat your lunchbox?
便當本來就要吃啊
Lunch is essential! Of course I have to eat it.
你還蠻會開玩笑的嘛
You think you're very funny, huh?
你到底有沒有羞恥心啊
Have you no shame?
手舉高一點
Raise your arms higher.
再高一點
Raise them higher.
你是沒吃飯是不是
So weak! Didn't you eat?
出去外面跳十圈再進來
Go do 10 rounds of squat jumps outside.
我有叫你放下來嗎
Did I ask you to put your hands down?
舉高
Higher!
I say to you today
my friends
that in spite of the difficulties and frustrations of the moment
I still have a dream
I still have a dream.
It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream
I have a dream
that one day this nation will rise up.
沈佳宜如果不是那麼假正經 其實還滿可愛的
(Shen Chia-Yi would be kind of cute if she wasn't such a prude)
and live up the true meaning of its dream.
你在想什麼啊
What are you thinking?
一整天都怪怪的
You've been weird all day long.
沒有啊
Nothing.
要不要帶你去收驚啊
Do you need an exorcism?
你想太多了
You are thinking too much.
訓導處報告
Head office announcement
三年二班周傑倫
Jay Chou in third year
馬上到訓導處來
please come to the head office now.
哎唷 屌哦
Sweet.
幹嘛啊
What?
昨天謝謝
Thank you for yesterday.
沒差 反正我臉皮厚
No big deal. I have no shame anyway.
謝謝
Thank you.
我看你乾脆請我喝飲料好了
Why not just buy me a drink?
不然一直聽你說謝謝 很奇怪
It's weird to hear you keep on saying "thank you".
我可以問你一個問題嗎
Can I ask you a question?
問啊
Go ahead.
你幹嘛不讀書
Why don't you want to study?
沒有不讀啊
It's not like I don't want to
要是我認真唸書起來
I am afraid if I really tried
實力強到連我自己都會害怕
I would be so good that I would even scare myself.
小心我一唸書
You better watch out then if I do study
立刻就把妳幹掉
I would beat you immediately.
挑一下啊
Wanna take up the challenge?
怕你喔
Sure, why not.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng.
幹嘛
What?
這是我自己出的考卷
This is a quiz I made up myself.
你拿回家寫
Take it and do it at home.
明天帶來給我改
Bring it back tomorrow.
真的假的啦
Are you for real?
還愛心考卷
A quiz made out of love.
還有這本數學參考書
And here is a math exercise book.
我用黃色螢光筆劃下來的地方算三遍
See the questions I've highlighted in yellow? Do them three times.
下次小考應該就有五十分了
You will probably score at least 50% in the next quiz.
才五十
Only 50%
我沒說考好成績很容易呀
I didn't say it's easy to get good grades
算完了基本題
I will give you some harder problems
我再出難一點的給你
after you finish the basics.
欠你錢喔
What do I owe you?
我幹嘛聽你的
Why should I listen to you?
因為我不想瞧不起你
Because I don't want to look down on you.
媽啦
Yeah right!
成績好就可以瞧不起人
You can be so stuck up just because you have good grades.
那你繼續好了 我又沒差
Go on then, I don't really care
我瞧不起的 不是成績不好的人
I don't look down on people with bad grades
我瞧不起的
I look down on you because
是一個明明自己不努力唸書
you pick on people with good grades
卻只會瞧不起用功唸書的人
while you don't even try to work hard.
穿衣服啦
Put on some clothes.
不然會感冒
Otherwise you'll catch a cold.
哪有可能
That's impossible.
我師父是李小龍耶
My master is Bruce Lee.
吞下去再說
Swallow your food before you speak.
你衛生紙怎麼用那麼快啊
Why is our tissue paper running out so fast?
幹嘛
What?
考卷
Your quiz.
你錯很多耶
You made so many mistakes.
你回去沒看參考書就直接寫了 對不對
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
這兩題 你可以從參考書上找解答
You can find the answers for these two problems in the exercise book.
這一題比較難
This one is harder.
不是背公式就可以解的
It's not the kind of problem you can solve with a formula.
需要用到這裡跟這裡的概念
You need to use these theories.
我圈起來了 你回去自己看
You go home and read the parts I circled.
唸書好煩
It's such a pain to study.
所以會唸書的人很厲害啊
That's why people who are good at studying rule.
你為什麼要盯柯景騰唸書啊
Why are you helping Ko Ching-Teng to study?
他成績能看嗎
Did you see his grades?
也不干你的事啊
It's none of your business.
真的很爛耶
They are really bad.
那也不干你的事啊
Still, it has nothing to do with you.
來 小姐 這是你的 這是你的
Miss, this is yours and this is yours.
謝謝老闆
Thank you!
謝謝
真不像你
It's so not you
我討厭什麼都不努力 卻一點也沒有自覺的人
I hate people who are lazy and have no sense of self-awareness at all.
喔
Ok
我又不是在說你
I'm not talking about you.
沒有在說我啊
You sure?
唸書好無聊哦
It's so boring to study
為什麼沈佳宜可以這樣每天唸書咧
I don't understand why Shen Chia-Yi can do this every day.
你說說看啊
Do you have any idea?
我跟你說哦
Let me tell you.
這種尖酸的題目就算解得出來
Being able to solve these tricky math questions.
對人生還是一點幫助都沒有啦
Does nothing good in life!
來
Here.
怎麼那麼用功啊
Why do you work so hard?
沒有啊 隨便念
No, I just study when I feel like it.
要念就要認真念
If you want to study, study hard then.
什麼隨便念
What do you mean "when you feel like it"?
好啦 我考慮一下
Fine, I will think about it.
吃稀飯
Eat porridge.
省著點用喔
Don't finish it too quickly.
對了
By the way
老闆前幾天剛進一批新貨 都沒有拆
there was a new shipment in the store a few days ago. The whole package was unopened
可是他要整盒賣
so the store owner wants to sell the whole thing together.
所以你們覺得要買整盒的SKYBOX 還是兩盒CC啊
Do you think I should buy the whole package of SKYBOX or two boxes of CC?
SKYBOX太貴了
SKYBOX is too expensive.
所以兩盒CC囉
So, two boxes of CC?
你昨天是打幾次啊
How many times did you jerk off yesterday?
這麼想睡哦
Why are you so tired?
打你的頭啦
Jerk off your ass.
你自己頭自己打 不要打我的啦
Mind your own business.
幹
Fuck!
起來吃肉圓啦
Get up and eat your meatballs.
你不吃 我把你吃掉喔
If you don't eat it, I'm going to finish yours, too.
沈佳宜 你看 新魔術
Shen Chia-Yi, check out my new magic.
你白癡耶
You idiot.
該邊 還不錯喔
Not bad!
太噁了啦
Gross!
他今年變過最好的
It's the best this year.
今年最好的對不對
Isn't it?
你們在幹嘛
What are you guys doing?
新魔術啦
It's a new magic.
真的假的 我要看我要看
For real? Show me! Show me!
我變一次給你看
I will show you.
超噁的
It's gross.
就假裝有喝 其實沒有
Just pretend that you are drinking, but don't swallow it.
你很遜耶
You suck.
你好噁喔你
You are so gross.
訂正
Make correction
十分鐘
10 minutes.
依我的聰明才智
Because I am so damn smart
五分鐘就綽綽有餘了
5 minutes is more than enough.
要念出來念啦
Don't study in the toilet
恁母啊 我尿快要閃出來了啦
I am going to pee in my pants.
媽 你不要嚇我啦
Ma, stop scaring me.
我嚇你幹嘛啦
Why would I?
棒棒咧緊出來
Dump it out and come out.
快啦
Hurry up.
這晚還不睏
Why are you up so late?
咧衝三小啊
What the hell are you doing in there?
在念英文啦
I am studying English
英文以後用不到啦
English is useless for you
I FUCK YOU
好睏啊啦
Go to sleep
I sleep late because I study English very hard.
謝明和
Hsieh Ming-Ho
八十七分
87%
好 不錯不錯
Not bad, not bad.
繼續努力
Keep it up
張家琪
Chang Chia-Chi
四十四分
44%
家琪要加油喔
Work harder.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng
七十五分
75%
最近有比較用功喔
You have been studying hard lately?
沒有啦 天才
Not really, I am a genius.
那都要這樣天才喔
Then, be a genius from now on.
好啦 下課
Okay, Class dismiss.
記住 下禮拜還要考試哦
Remember the test next week.
還天才啊
Genius?
真敢講耶
Are you serious?
其實會解這種題目有什麼了不起的
It's not a big deal that you know how to solve these problems
我敢跟妳賭
I bet you
十年後我連Log是什麼都不知道
in 10 years time, I wouldn't even know what log is
還是可以活得好好的
and it makes no difference to my life.
嗯
Emmmm...
妳不相信
You don't believe me?
我相信啊
I do.
相信妳還那麼用功讀書
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生本來就有很多事是徒勞無功的啊
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
妳真的很喜歡學大人講道理耶
You really like to pitch high notes like adults, don't you?
像你這麼幼稚 對你的人生一點幫助也沒有
It will be no help to your life whatsoever if you continue to be so childish like this.
妳又沒做過
How would you know
妳怎麼知道
if you've never been childish ever?
很多事不用做就知道沒有意義啊
You know something is meaningless without trying it.
爛斃了
This is shit.
來 下一隊
Next group
聽說被殭屍咬到也會變殭屍
I heard you will become a zombie if you are bitten by one
我不相信這件事
I don't buy that.
這件事一定是假的啊
This must be some rumors.
可是我覺得一定是有個依據 他才會講
But he had to learn this from somewhere, right?
怎麼辦
What are we going to do?
喂
Hey.
幹嘛
What?
你有沒有聽到 大家最近都在聊的傳說啊
Have you heard that rumor lately?
我很帥這件事已經變傳說囉
You mean the one that every girl wants to date me?
白癡
Moron.
好啦 幹嘛
Okay, what is it?
聽說有一批大陸偷渡客 偷渡到一半就淹死了
I heard some stowaways from China were drowned.
屍體被衝上岸後
And they had became zombies
都變成殭屍了耶
after their bodies were washed up on shore.
喔 你說那群殭屍喔
Oh! Those zombies
我知道啊
I've heard about them.
他們就沿路一直跳一直跳一直跳
They jumped, jumped and jumped all the way here.
媽啦
Shit.
那是真的嗎
Are you for real?
廢話
Of course.
一堆人晚上不睡覺 在山上跳跳跳
With whole bunch of people jumping around up in the hills at night
不是殭屍是什麼
what do you think they are?
我記得前幾天報紙也有寫吧
Yes, I remember seeing that on the newspaper a few days ago.
如果他們努力一點的話
If they jumped harder
現在應該已經跳到八卦山了
they should have reached Baguashan Mountain by now.
怎樣 要去看嗎
So, do you want to see them?
誰要去看啊
No way
可是就算是真的 要看也看不到吧
I don't think you can see them even if they are real.
說不定他們在八卦山上迷了路
Maybe they got lost in Baguashan Mountain
就直接跳進彰化市區了啊
and jumped directly into Changhua city.
別說不可能
Don't think it's impossible.
殭屍又沒有方向感
Zombies don't have a sense of direction.
幹嘛
What?
你最近跟沈佳宜好像很有話聊
You and Shen Chia-Yi seem to have a lot to talk about lately.
幫我一個忙
Do me a favor.
該不會是
No way.
寫情書這種爛梗吧
Don't tell me you want to write a love letter?
你寫好
You write it
我照抄
and I copy it
可是一瓶飲料好像不夠耶
I don't think one drink is enough
幫我告白成功的話
if she says yes
我請你一年份
I will buy you one year worth.
加一張Grant Hill 100:1明星賽球員卡
Plus a Grant Hill 100:1 All-Star Card.
好 一言為定
Alright, deal.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng.
你晚上有沒有要補習
Are you going to cram school tonight?
補個屁呀
What for?
你這麼笨 還不補習
You are so dumb, how can you not go!
你管我
Mind your own business.
今天晚上開始
Starting tonight
你留在學校唸書
you stay here and study after school.
晚上留校
Stay at school?
有沒有搞錯啊
What's your problem?
我也會留啊
I will stay, too.
哪招啊
What the hell?
原來沈佳宜只要沒有補習
It turned out that Shen Chia-Yi stayed behind to study
都會一個人留在學校唸書
when she didn't have to go to cram school.
欸 你是不是怕那群偷渡上岸的殭屍跳到這裡
So, you asked me to stay behind at school with you
才叫我陪你啊
only because you are afraid of those zombies, right?
我是怕你笨
I am just worried you're getting stupid.
對了
Right.
這裡有封信 是老曹叫我拿給你的
Tsao asked me to give you this letter.
我親愛的沈佳宜同學
My dear Shen Chia-Yi
我很喜歡你
I like you very much.
俗話說：Nothing's gonna change my love for you
As the song goes, "Nothing's gonna change my love for you.
Making love out of nothing at all
勉強可以表達我對你的感覺
barely expresses my feelings for you.
這是你的字耶
This is your handwriting.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng
我不得不說耶
I must say
你寫情書的文筆 真的很差耶
you suck at writing love letters.
哪可能
What do you mean?
明明就寫得氣勢非凡好不好
I am that close to William Shakespeare, okay?
有時間幫人家寫情書啊
Since you have the time to write love letters for someone else.
不如用這些時間拿去背單字
Why don't you use the time to memorize some English vocabulary?
說真的
Ok.
雖然我很帥 人聰明 又會講笑話
Even though I am cute, smart and incredibly humorous
但妳不要輕易的喜歡上我
don't fall in love with me easily.
因為我是孤獨的 風中一匹狼
Because I am a lone wolf traveling in the wild wind.
謝謝喔
Oh, thanks
我又不喜歡比我笨的男生
I'm not interested in guys who are dumber than me.
沈佳宜不喜歡比她笨的男生
Shen Chia-Yi doesn't like guys that are dumber than her.
笨
Dumb?
我是怕搶了妳全校第一名的頭銜
Come on, I let you win on purpose
才一直忍妳 讓妳
I don't study hard cause I don't want to beat you
故意輸給妳 好不好
and I don't want to hurt your feelings!
這怎麼好意思啊
Pardon me.
拜託你不用這麼忍耐
Save your kindness, mister. You are welcome to try to beat me anytime!
敢不敢 跟我打一個賭
I dare you to bet with me.
賭
Let's bet on...
頭髮
Your hair.
怎麼賭
How?
如果妳月考考贏我的話
If you beat me in the next midterm
妳要怎麼整我都可以
you can do whatever you want to me.
但如果我考贏妳的話
But, if I won
妳要綁一個月的馬尾
you will have to wear a ponytail for a month.
隨便啊
Sure, whatever.
反正又不可能
It's not like you would win anyway!
這種超雞巴的自信 我又被電到了
I was struck by her cocky confidence right away.
喂
Hey, you.
三更半夜不睡覺
Why on earth you need to study freaking English
背什麼死人骨頭英文
in the middle of the night?
I fuck you
I fuck you too
I fuck your mother.
你幹嘛 幹嘛啦
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you fuck you
I love you
I LOVE YOU
老闆
Hey, Ma'am.
來碗超帥的光頭
A super hot and charming jar head, please.
三八啦 光頭哪有帥的
Idiot, how can a jar head be handsome?
有啦
Of course there is.
不信你剪剪看
Give it a try if you don't believe me.
不欠你啦
Here, I don't owe you any more.
不要弄啦
Stop that.
我在補習班聽說
Rumor has it that Inoue Takehiko has died a couple weeks ago!
井上雄彥啊 前幾個禮拜出車禍死了
I heard that he died in a car accident.
是喔
Really.
難怪我感覺他畫風有點變
No wonder I felt something was different in his drawing style.
突然變強而已 這種天才怎麼可能說死就死啊
More powerful that is, how can such a genius die just like that.
你覺不覺得
Don't you think...
覺得怎樣
Think What?
你覺不覺得沈佳宜有點喜歡我
Don't you think Shen Chia-Yi likes me?
不然今天怎麼綁馬尾
If not, why would she wear a ponytail today?
也許喔
Maybe!
沈佳宜怎麼知道我喜歡綁馬尾的女生啊
How did Shen Chia-Yi know I like girls who wear ponytails?
是嗎
You too?
我一直一直都很喜歡綁馬尾的女生啊
I always like girls who wear ponytails.
我也是
So do!
我不知道沈佳宜為什麼贏了還要綁馬尾
I don't know why Shen Chia-Yi wore a ponytail that day even though she won the bet.
但從此以後
However, ever since then
努力用功讀書竟然變成一件非常熱血的事
studying hard had become an enthusiastic thing for me.
幾千塊錢的班費 不見了
The class funds went missing.
第六節課的時候 班長檢查還在
It was still here when the class leader checked about an hour ago.
現在要放學了
Now school is almost finished.
偷錢的人 還會有誰
Who else could have stolen that money?
一定是你們班上自己的同學
It must be someone sitting in this classroom!
把錢偷走的再不自首的話
Whoever stole that money, you better turn yourself in right now.
就不要怪教官不客氣
Otherwise, don't blame me for being too harsh afterwards.
好
Fine.
不敢承認也沒有關係
It's okay if no one wants to admit it
反正這個小偷 就在你們這個班上
I guarantee that the thief is sitting right here in this room.
他一定覺得自己很聰明
The person must thinks that he can get away with this.
好
Good
很好
very good.
現在每一個人把紙筆拿出來
Now, take out your pen, everyone.
寫下你認為可能是小偷的人的名字
And write down the name of the person that you think it's most likely to be the thief.
投票結果前三名
The top three named
把書包倒在講台上 讓我檢查
will have to bring your bags forward, and I will check them personally.
立刻
Now!
馬上把隨堂測驗紙拿出來
Take out your paper right now.
曹國勝
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
你幹什麼
What are you doing?
教官
Sir.
你憑什麼叫我們懷疑自己的同學
Who do you think you are to have us suspect our own classmates?
我是教官 還是你是教官
Now who is the supervisor? Are you or am I?
你是教官
You are, sir.
但你是個爛人啦
But you are an ass hole!
你說什麼
What did you say?
我說你爛人
I said you are an asshole.
柯景騰 曹國勝
Ko Ching-Teng, Tsao Kuo-Sheng
我看你們兩個是做賊心虛
I think you guys are bluffing
把你們的書包給我拿過來 第一個檢查
bring your bags now and I will check yours first.
報告教官
Excuse me, Sir.
你不可以這樣
You have no right to do that
不可以怎麼樣
I have no right to do what?
不可以叫我們投這種票
You can't ask us to write down names and vote on such a thing.
不可以叫我們懷疑自己的同學
You can't ask us to suspect our own classmates.
大不了大家再把錢繳一次就好了
We can just all pay the fees again.
這也沒什麼
It's no big deal.
對啊
Exactly.
再繳一次就好了嘛
We can just pay again.
妳不要以為你成績好 說什麼都沒有關係
Being an honor student doesn't mean that you can say whatever you want.
把你的書包拿過來
Bring your bag over here.
我們不要
No way.
我們又不是小偷
We are not thieves.
爛人
Douche.
你說什麼
What did you say?
爛人啦
I said you are a douchebag.
統統把書包給我拿過來
Bring your bags over now, all of you.
不要
No.
教官
Sir
我現在合理的懷疑你沒有小雞雞
I now suspect that you have no balls.
褲子脫下
Take your pants off now.
你說什麼
What did you say?
褲子脫下啦
Take your pants off.
把書包拿過來
Bring your bags over.
要就給你啦
Fine, here you go!
你們不要一直看我
Stop staring at me.
我覺得很丟臉
It's very embarrassing. I feel so ashamed.
一點都不丟臉啊
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
妳超厲害的耶
You kicked ass!
半蹲不用太認真啦
Don't need to be too serious about this.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
稍微休息一下
Relax a bit.
蹲個意思意思就好了啊
Just pretend, it's no big deal.
反正那些老師根本沒在看
Those teachers are not watching anyway.
偶爾當一下壞學生 很爽的
It's kind of nice to be a bad student once in a while, isn't it?
好丟臉
I am so ashamed.
認識妳從國中到現在
Ever since I knew you from junior high
剛剛是我唯一覺得妳比我厲害的時候
that was the only time I was amazed by how tough you really are.
沈佳宜 妳超正點的耶
Shen Chia-Yi, you rock!
哭起來也超正的
You look so pretty even when you cry.
對啊
Yeah.
超正的
Super duper cool.
令人刮目相看
Unbelievably cool.
不像考卷 所有複雜困難的問題都能得到一個解答
Unlike quizzes
真實人生裡有些事永遠也沒有答案
you never find a correct answer in life.
到底是誰偷了班費 沒有人知道
No one really knew who stole our money, but no one really cared.
只記得 那天的沈佳宜真的
All I remembered from that day was Shen Chia-Yi's face
好美 好美
beautifully and delicately engraved in my heart.
六年前 剛剛踏進精誠中學國中部的時候
Six years ago, when we first stepped in to Jing-Cheng high school
十二歲的我們懵懵懂懂
we were all young and immature.
雖然對於未來有無限的想像
Although we had great dreams about our future
卻不知道能在這裡學習到什麼 收穫到什麼
we weren't really sure what we were going to learn and encounter during these years.
幸好一路上有師長的諄諄教誨
Thanks to the teachers who led us and furnished us with abundant knowledge.
同學們也建立了深厚的情誼
Thanks to all the peers who accompanied us throughout the years
一起經歷困難挫折 也一起攜手成長
with bitter and sweet memories.
我說 精誠中學就是我們的青春
Ching-Chen high school represents our young and crazy days
也是最美好的行囊
it gave us the most wonderful times of our life.
畢業典禮後
From now on
讓我們用力的張開翅膀 飛向各自不同的夢想
it's time for us to spread our wings and chase our dreams.
各位同學
So long, my friends.
我們珍重再見
真羨慕妳
How I envy you.
國中三年 高中三年 都有這麼多人追妳
You have so many guys chasing after you throughout the years!
被喜歡其實是很不錯
Yes, it's quite nice to be liked by someone.
但是
But...
妳該不會想說被這麼多人追 其實很困擾吧
Don't tell me that you feel annoyed because you are too popular.
不是啦
No
我只是覺得 自己是個很幸福的人
I just think that I am a very lucky girl.
那妳決定好了嗎
So, have you decided?
決定什麼
Decided what?
決定跟誰在一起啊
Decided whom you want to be with.
幹嘛啊 連我都不能說喔
Come on, you can't even tell me?
如果…
Ok, if...
…我會很高興的
I will be really happy.
畢業快樂
Happy graduation.
終於 聯考了
Finally, the colleague entrance exam came.
對我來說 聯考好像不是去考大學
To me, the exam was more like a test for Shen Chia-Yi's special training programs
而是驗收沈佳宜對我的特訓成果
rather than an exam for college.
升大學前 最後一個夏天的主題 是咸咸的海水
We spent most of our time at the beach during the summer before college.
真的很幼稚
They are so childish
超幼稚的
I know, so childish.
你應該不太喜歡幼稚的男生吧
You don't really like childish guys, do you?
嗯
No.
那你覺得裡面誰最幼稚
Who do you think is the most childish one among them all.
柯騰吧
Ko-Teng, maybe?
那我呢
How about me?
你很幼稚耶
You are so childish.
畢業了耶
Now that we have graduated
你們有沒有想過以後要幹嘛
have you thought about what you want to do in the future?
我想去科學園區上班
I want to work in the Hsinchu Science and Industrial Park
分股票 賺大錢
so I can get stocks for bonuses and tons of money.
然後娶沈佳宜
And then I can marry Shen Chia-Yi...
或胡家瑋
or Hu Chia-Wei.
誰要嫁給你啊
Who wants to marry you?
我想出國唸書耶
I want to study abroad.
你出國很浪費錢啦
It'll be such a waste of money, okay?
你靠腰哦
Oh, fuck off.
出國唸書
Study abroad?
我也想出國唸書
I want to study abroad, too.
去申請公費留學 念MBA
Maybe I will apply for government scholarships and get an MBA degree
我想一直打籃球下去 打進校隊
I want to keep on playing basketball.
最後打進美國職籃
And maybe one day make my way to NBA.
家瑋呢
What about you, Chia-Wei?
我啊
Me?
找個有錢人嫁掉就好啦
I think I will find myself a rich man to marry.
干你屁事
Go away.
沈佳宜咧
What about you, Shen Chia-Yi?
我對自己的未來 其實沒有太多想像
I don't expect much about my future, really.
還有一個人還沒說耶
Ko-Teng, it's your turn
我想成為一個很厲害的人
I want to be a kickass person.
你這有說跟沒說根本一樣嘛
What are you talking about?
怎樣才是厲害的人啊
What is a kickass person?
讓這個世界因為有了我 而有一點點的不一樣
I want the world to be a little bit better because of me.
而我的世界 不過就是妳的心
And you are the only person that is going to make my world better.
喂 幹嘛
Hello. Yes?
我只會唸書
I am a nerd
I am a bookworm.
從國中到高中
Ever since junior high and high school.
我就只會唸書
All I did was studying
卻還是考不好
I still screwed it up.
不管妳念哪間學校
No matter which university you go to
有件事 我想跟妳說
there is something that I want to say to you.
拜託你
Please.
不要現在跟我講你喜歡我
Don't tell me you like me now
我喜歡妳
I do like you
妳早就知道了啊
and you knew that already.
那你要跟我說什麼啦
What do you want to tell me, then?
聯考放榜了
The results were out.
阿和考上了清大經濟
A-Ho got into Economics Major in National Tsing Hua University
朝未來出國留學的路邁進
which means he made one step forward to his overseas dream.
該邊考上了逢甲資工
Groin got into Information Engineering at Feng Chia University
也算是踏上了科學園區之路
to become one of those Science Park smart engineers.
老曹呢 考上了成大化工
Tsao got into Chemical Engineering at Cheng Kung University.
看樣子以後要去美國職籃是有一點難度
So I guess it's most unlikely that he would make it into NBA.
沈佳宜雖然失常
Although Shen Chia-Yi didn't do as well as she expected
但還是考上了師範學院
she still got into University of Education
想到將來沈佳宜當老師的樣子 就覺得非常適合她
I could totally imagine Shen Chia-Yi being a teacher, it really suits her.
送你
Here, for you.
這什麼
What is this?
我自己畫的
I drew it myself.
有點醜
Not my best work
不過還可以
but I think it's okay.
謝謝囉
Thanks.
沈佳宜 上大學以後
Shen Chia-Yi, promise me something.
不要太快讓別的男生追到妳
Don't let boys get you too soon after you go to college.
好不好
Ok?
你在說什麼啊
What are you talking about?
(你是我最珍貴的人）
You Are the Apple of My Eye.
喔 對了 還有勃起
Oh, yes, as for the masturbating Boner.
一直打手槍的勃起 重考
He decided to stay and take the college entrance exam again.
重考 重考 陪我重考啦
Take the entrance exam next year with me please!
我也來到人生的下一站
I have also come to the next stage in my life
一間沒有沈佳宜的大學
a school without Shen Chia-Yi
沒想到我第一個牽手的女孩 不是沈佳宜
I never thought that Shen Chia-Yi would not be the first girl that I hold hands with.
而是 而是一個叫
Instead of her, it was a girl named...
叫什麼
Named...
你好 我叫許可欣
Hello, my name was Hsu Ke-Shin.
你好 我叫柯景騰
Hi, my name is Ko Ching-Teng.
宿舍有很多奇奇怪怪的傳說
There were many weird stories in the dormitory.
大部分都跟鬼有關
Most of them were ghost stories.
不過
But
其中有一個跟四腳獸有關的傳說
there's one story about a four-legged beast.
絕對是真的
It was definitely real...
我的室友來自四面八方
My roommates came from all walks of life.
孝綸是個肌肉狂 整天舉啞鈴
Hsiao-Lun was a muscle maniac, who did nothing but lifted weights all day long.
超級宅的義智
The ultimate weirdo is Yi-Chi.
隨時都在看動漫 幾乎不去上課
He was never in the classroom because he's always reading Manga.
從大一就開始準備考研究所的建漢
Chien-Han, who started to prepare for graduate school from the day he arrived
無時無刻都在唸書
was studying twenty four seven.
幸好 我們還有共通的話題
Luckily, we had some common interests to talk about.
是不是 飯島愛太老了
See, Iijima Ai is way too old.
奶頭都黑掉了
Her tits have turned dark.
小澤圓看起來比較可口
Emmm... Madoza Ozawa looks hotter and yummier
大浦安娜也不錯
Anna Ohura is not too bad, either
我那邊有個叫人類補奸計劃的好東西
I have some nice stuff called the Human Sex Program.
等一下一起看啊
Let's watch it together later.
看卡通人物做愛 也太奇怪了吧
Don't you think it's too weird to watch cartoon characters having sex?
還有跟狗 還有跟鰻魚的咧
There're ones with dogs and eels, too.
那是手機還沒普及的年代
That was the time before mobile phones were common.
到了晚上一堆男生就像集體中邪一樣
At night, all the guys acted like they casted a spell.
在公共電話前大排長龍
Everyone one of us was lining up in front the telephone booth
小可愛 我好想你喔
I miss you so much my sweetie little pumpkin pie
每個小時都固定想你十次啊
I miss you 10 times every hour on a regular basis.
真的啊
It's true.
那你有沒有好想我
So do you miss me this much, too?
一個小時想幾次
How many times per hour?
有沒有十次
10 times at least?
喂
Hey.
喂 你還沒睡吧
You are not asleep yet, are you?
還沒啊
No, not yet.
快睡啦
Go to sleep
每天晚上我都跟沈佳宜講電話
I talked to Shen Chia-Yi every night.
有時講到她睡著
Sometimes, she fell asleep in the middle of our conversations.
有時講到我連吃飯的錢都用光光
Sometimes I spent all my money on phone calls and left no money for food.
迎新晚會下禮拜啊
Welcome party? Next week.
下禮拜
Next week.
那我跟妳說喔
Listen.
妳可不可以不要下去跳舞
Can you please not dance with anyone?
不要下去跳舞 為什麼
Why not?
因為
Because...
雖然我還沒追到妳啊
Ok, I know we are not seeing each other yet.
不過那些追都沒追過妳的男生
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼可以牽妳的手
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我自己都沒牽過耶
I haven't even held them myself.
那你呢
What about you?
你沒下去跳啊
You didn't dance with anyone?
我就不相信你沒有牽其他女生的手
I don't believe you didn't hold any girl's hands.
是有稍微牽一下啦
Oh, well... yeah, but only a little bit.
不過那是因為
That's because...
我把對方想成妳啊
I imagined that she was you.
你少噁心了 我才不相信咧
Oh please, I don't believe you.
真的啦
Really.
那我也可以把對方想成是你啊
Then I can also imagine the guy I dance with was you.
不要鬧啦
No man, I'm for real.
好啦 說真的喔
All right, I am serious.
不可以被牽喔
Don't let anyone hold your hands.
嗯 掰掰
Bye.
終於上大學後的第一個聖誕節來了
Finally, it was the first Christmas after we entered college.
喂
Hey.
我們這樣算約會嗎
Is this considered a date?
幹嘛問我
Why ask me?
台北怎麼那麼冷
Why is it so cold in Taipei?
換我換我 快點
Hurry up, my turn for a picture!
快點啦 快走了
Hurry up! It's leaving.
沒有拍到
Oops, I didn't get it.
你
You.
不要跑
Come back.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng.
你真的很喜歡我嗎
Do you really like me a lot?
喜歡啊
Yes, I do.
很喜歡啊
Very much
我總覺得你把我想得太好了
I always feel that you give me too much credit
我根本沒有你想的那麼好
I'm not as good as you think
你喜歡我 讓我覺得有點怪怪的
I feel weird about the fact that you like me.
哪裡奇怪
What's so weird about it?
我也會有你不知道的一面啊
There is another side of me that you don't know about
在家裡我也會很邋遢
I am very sloppy at home.
嗯…
Emm...
也會有起床氣
I get very grumpy when I wake up early.
也會因為一點小事就跟我妹發脾氣
And I get pissed off with my little sister at times just for minor stuff
我就
I am... you know.
很普通啊
Very ordinary.
說不定你喜歡上的
Maybe, the person that you like
只是你想像出來的我
is in your imagination
我沒那麼會想像
I am not that imaginative.
真的
Look.
你仔細想想
Think carefully.
你有那麼喜歡我嗎
Do you like me that much?
喜歡啊
Hell yeah.
你很幼稚耶
You are so childish.
你都沒有仔細想
You didn't even think through it.
你想好再跟我說
Think about it carefully before you tell me.
沈佳宜是什麼意思呢
What did Shen Chia-Yi mean?
她是不是想委婉的拒絕我呢
Was she trying to turn me down in a nice way?
我很害怕
I was afraid.
一直以來 我都以為我自己是個超有自信的人
For a long time, I always thought that I am a confident guy.
但那時我才發現
At that moment, I realized that
原來在喜歡的女孩面前 我是個膽小鬼
I was really a coward in front of the girl I liked.
妳許什麼願啊
What do you wish for?
自己寫自己的 不可以偷看
Write your own, no peeking.
這麼小氣
Come on, I just want to have a look.
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi
我很喜歡妳
I like you very much
非常喜歡妳
I like you a lot.
總有一天 我一定要追到妳
One day you will be mine.
百分之一千萬 一定會追到妳
One day, I will make you mine.
你想知道答案嗎
Do you want to know the answer?
我現在就可以告訴你
I can tell you right now.
不要
No
我沒有問妳
I didn't ask you.
所以妳也不可以拒絕我
So you can't turn me down.
你真的不想知道
You really don't want to know?
拜託不要現在告訴我
Please don't tell me now.
請讓我 繼續喜歡妳
Just let me keep on liking you.
每一個男生都想在自己心上人面前
Every guy wants to show his strongest side.
展現自己最強的一面
Especially in front of the girl he likes.
而我又應該展現什麼給沈佳宜看呢
So what should I show to Shen Chia-Yi?
我想了很久 終於有一天我悟出了答案
It took me a long time before the answer suddenly hit me one day.
你就去廁所尿尿 是會怎樣啊
Why can't you just go pee in the toilet?
很遠耶
Man, it's far.
你要出門啊
Hey, are you going out?
順便幫我拿去倒一下
Empty this for me on your way out, will you?
有沒有搞錯啊
You fucking serious?
幫同學倒尿 也是友情的…
Come on, just do me a favor...
你們不覺得
Don't you guys think.
是時候戰鬥了嗎
It's time to battle?
我們來
Come on.
打架吧
Let's fight
我要辦比賽
I am organizing a competition.
有沒有人要參加的
Anyone wants to join me?
有沒有人要參加比賽
Anyone wants to join the competition?
有沒有人要打架的
Anyone wants to fight?
我有辦打架比賽
Fighting competition, anyone?
要不要參加比賽
Do you want to fight in a competition?
要不要參加格鬥比賽
Do you want to fight in a combat tournament?
有沒有人要打架
Anyone wants to fight?
有沒有人要
Anyone wants to join?
我可以 看完嗎
Can I stay until you guys finish?
一般運動有什麼了不起
What's the big deal with the regular sports?
當然自由格鬥比較屌啊
Combat is definitely cooler.
真的啦 妳一定要來看喔
Seriously, you have to be here
我剛已經貼出海報了
I just put out posters.
到時候一定大爆滿
It's going to be a full house.
你為什麼要辦這麼危險的比賽
Why do you want to organize such a dangerous competition?
你們學校都不用唸書的嗎
Don't you guys need to study and look after your marks?
就是因為大家都只會唸書
Exactly! People study way too hard.
所以才需要運動一下
That's why they need to exercise
我要幫他們特訓
I want to give them some trainings.
還不就是打架
It's just a fight.
這麼說 也可以啦
Fine, if you really want to put it that way
有時候 我真的很不瞭解你
I really don't get you sometimes.
簡單啦
You can nail this easily
我以為大學裡都是娘炮
I thought everyone in college was a pussy
我錯了
I was wrong.
有個硬漢叫建偉
There was a tough guy named Chien-Wei.
他是胎拳社的副主將 黑帶
He was the second chair of the taekwondo club, a black belt.
看起來很臭屁
He looked cocky.
看起來很強
And he looked tough.
正合我意
Just the kind of guy that I was looking for.
比照天下第一武道大會的規定
We follow the rules of the highest martial arts order in the world.
不可以殺死對方
No killing.
不可以出界
You cannot go outside of the boundaries.
不可以踢小雞雞
No kicking on penises.
倒地後數到十沒有爬起來也算輸
You lose if you are knocked down and unable to get up after the referee counts to 10.
預備
Ready!
穿上
Put it on.
三小啊
What the hell?
穿上它 我才敢打你
Wear it so I know I won't kill you.
穿你的屁股啦
Go fuck yourself.
開始
Go
我要殺死你
I am going to kill you.
快 羚羊拳
Punch him with Gazelle punch.
站起來
Stand up.
柯騰
Ko-Teng.
趕快啦
Hurry up.
快反擊
Fight back.
柯騰 快反擊
Ko-Teng, fight back.
打他的肝臟
Beat him up.
站起來 打他 起來
Stand up and beat him, stand up.
1…2…3…4…5…6…7…
One... Two... Three... Four... Five... Six... Seven.
柯騰 站起來
Ko-Teng stand up.
你再不起來
Stand up now.
我就要數完了耶
Time is running out.
柯騰
Ko-Teng.
快反擊
Fight back.
那誰 好正喔
Who is that? She's so hot.
剛剛比賽結束的時候 我都沒有看到妳
Hey! I didn't see you when the game was over
我還以為被打昏了耶
I thought I was knocked out...
妳剛剛有看到那男的嗎
Did you see that guy?
他超厲害的耶
He kicked my ass so bad
我一直閃不開他的腳
I couldn't get away from him.
很好玩嗎
Was it fun?
還不錯啊
Not bad!
妳來看 我超開心的耶
I was so excited when I saw you!
我問你 很好玩嗎
Answer my question, was it fun?
幹嘛啦
Now what?
你辦這什麼奇怪的比賽啊
Why did you insist on organizing such a weird competition?
你辦這比賽的意義到底在哪裡
What's the meaning of it?
妳不覺得很炫嗎
Don't you think it's super cool?
兩個男人之間 一定要分出勝負那種…
That kind of... win or lose between two men.
還不就是打架
It's just violence.
柯景騰
Ko Ching-Teng.
你特地辦一個比賽把自己搞受傷
You organized a game to get yourself hurt.
你怎麼會這麼幼稚啊
Why are you so childish?
幼稚
Childish?
對 就是幼稚
Right, childish.
很幼稚
Very childish.
我問你
Let me ask you something.
你辦這奇怪的比賽 到底讓你學到什麼
What exactly did you learn from this game?
學
"Learn"?
不見得做什麼事情都一定要學到什麼吧
Why do I have to learn something from everything that I do?
至少讓你學到了 辦這種比賽會受傷
At least you learned that having a competition like this will get yourself hurt.
而受這種傷一點必要都沒有
And it is totally unnecessary.
你真的很幼稚
You are so childish.
你身上的傷 我只能說是你活該
See those bruises on your face? You deserve it
我幼稚
I am childish?
妳知不知道這格鬥賽對我來說是很棒的經驗啊
Do you know this competition is a fantastic experience for me?
妳可不可以單純替我高興就好啊
Can't you just be happy for me?
你以後還要辦這種比賽
So you are going to do it again?
當然要辦啊
Of course I will do it again.
為什麼不辦
Why not?
幼稚
Grow up will you?
妳為什麼總要否定對我很重要的東西呀
Why do you always look down on things that matter to me?
對你很重要的東西 竟然是讓你傷害你自己嗎
Things that matter to you are things that hurt you?
對啦
Fine
我就是幼稚
I am childish.
才會追妳這種努力用功讀書的女生
And that's why I would go after such a good school girl like you
我就是幼稚 才有辦法追妳這麼久
I am this naive so I could chase you for so long.
那你就不要追了啊
Stop trying then.
笨蛋
Idiot.
對啦 我就是笨蛋啦
Right! I am an idiot.
大笨蛋
Moron.
大笨蛋才能追妳那麼久
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase after you for such a long time.
你什麼都不懂
You don't understand anything.
我就是什麼都不懂啦
No, I don't understand anything.
成長 最殘酷的部份就是
The cruelest part in “growing up”
女孩永遠比同年齡的男孩成熟
is that girls are always more mature than guys of the same age.
女孩的成熟 沒有一個男孩招架得住
No guys can handle girls at their age.
大吵一架
What? A big fight?
所以這次吵完架就不會在一起了喔
Does that mean you are not going to be a couple after this?
你有什麼毛病啊
What's your problem?
真的假的 不打算和好
For real? Not plans of making up?
也就是說我有機會囉
Oh yes, so I have a chance now?
老曹自以為熱血
Tsao took off right away on his motorcycle
騎著摩托車從台南直接衝到台北
and rode from Tainan to Taipei.
準備跟沈佳宜告白
He was ready to confess his love to Shen Chia-Yi.
阿和則買了最近一班的火車票
A-Ho, on the other hand, bought a ticket for the next train.
結論是
It turned out that
火車比較快
the train is faster
雖然我們一直很有話聊
I know we have always been good friends.
可是其實我早就知道你喜歡的是柯騰
But somehow I always knew that Ko-Teng is the one.
我一直學不會的事
Being childish is something that
就是你最討厭的幼稚
I can never learn.
可是每次你罵柯騰幼稚的時候 我都很嫉妒
Even though you said you hate childish guys.
因為其實你罵他幼稚的時候
Every time when you called Ko-Teng childish
真的很漂亮
I can tell how much you like that childishness in him.
你跟我說這些做什麼
Why are you telling me this now?
如果我什麼都不做
If I don't do anything now
你們遲早會和好
you guys will get back together eventually.
對不對
Right?
對不起
I am sorry.
這一次我想趁人之危
Since you guys are not in good terms now, I would like to take my chances.
看見那個畫面 老曹的機車重新發動繼續往前
When Tsao saw A-Ho and Shen Chia-Yi walked across the street, he took off again.
這一次 他不知不覺就繞了台灣整整一圈
This time, he rode his way around the whole island.
老曹繞回台南時
When Tsao made it to Tainan
因為恍神 醒來已經騎到了嘉義
he took the wrong exit so he went straight to Chiayi.
於是老曹乾脆又繼續往上騎 再接再厲又繞了台灣一圈
Then he thought why not just take another round around Taiwan.
不過這次他在中途停下來載我
This time, he stopped to picked me up.
幹嘛
What?
操
Fuck.
幹嘛
What do you want?
還手啦
Hit me back.
你以為我想啊
What's your freaking problem?
白癡耶
Idiot?
失戀了
I was heart broken
我失去了沈佳宜
I had lost Shen Chia-Yi.
我的青春 什麼都不剩了
There was nothing left in me
失戀那幾個月我認識了很多女生
I met quite a lot of girls after I lost Shen Chia-Yi.
只是那些女生的名字清一色都是四個字
It's just that they all happened to be Japanese.
為此我感到相當空虛
For that, I felt there was something missing in my heart.
櫻木花道說的好
Sakuragi Hanamichi was right.
左手只是輔助
You can only use one hand, your left hand.
因為右手要拿滑鼠
Because you need your right hand on the mouse.
我們這樣每天打手槍 到底有什麼意義
What's the point of us masturbating all day long?
意義是蝦小
Who cares?
林北只聽過精液
As long as I get to ejaculate, who cares!
沒聽過意義
I am coming, I am coming, I AM COMING!
現在光是大學畢業已經不夠
Even though getting a diploma might not be crucial
雖然說學歷並不代表一切
but a bachelor degree seems to be not enough
我跟阿和之間有很長一段時間沒有聯絡
I admit that I might be childish, just like how Shen Chia-Yi described me.
面對自己的好朋友
A-Ho has been a really good friend of mine.
卻連裝一下祝福的語氣都覺得勉強
But I just couldn't bring myself to congratulate him.
雖然我們現在念不同的大學
It'd be nice to plan things ahead.
可是我們可以討論看看研究所的方向
We should start thinking about graduate schools.
如果說妳是真的想當老師的話
If you really want to be a teacher.
那我建議妳可以去選教育研究所
Then getting a Master of education would be nice.
這樣子以後月薪也可以多一點嘛 幾千塊錢吧至少
At least people will pay you more in the future.
阿和和沈佳宜只在一起短短的五個月
A-Ho was with Shen Chia-Yi for only five months.
不過 那也夠讓我嫉妒的了
But that was more than enough to make me jealous like hell.
幹 有鬼啊
Fuck, what's happening?
靠北啊
Shit.
有鬼啊 有鬼啊
Fuck, what's going on!
快閃啊 閃啊 有鬼啊 有鬼殺來了
Ghost! Ghost! Let's get the hell out of here!
鬼在哪裡 鬼在哪裡
Shit... ghost? Where? Where?
太扯了
This is crazy, man!
我媽媽說 我家附近的旅館整個倒下來
My mom just called and said that the hotel next to my house just collapsed.
你家不是在台北嗎
You are from Taipei, aren't you?
震央在台北
So the epicenter is in Taipei?
這裡人太多了 基地台超載
It's too crowded here, the system is probably overloaded.
人少的地方搞不好才會通耶
Try to give it a shot at somewhere less crowded.
這理論對嗎
Are you sure?
不知道
I don't know.
喂
Hello.
柯騰啊
Ko-Teng?
我沒事
I am safe, don't worry.
可街上都是人耶
Everyone is out on the street, though.
嚇死我了
Thank god
我剛聽說震央在台北
I heard that the epicenter is in Taipei.
整個旅館都垮下來
And the whole building collapsed
總之
anyway.
你沒事就好
Good to hear that you are safe.
謝謝
Thank you.
那
Alright then
沒事我就…
better go.
我很感動
Wait a minute
真的
I am touched, really.
妳感動個頭啦
Yeah right.
妳可是我追了N年的女生耶
You are the girl that I chased for years!
要是妳不見了
Who else is going to share this memory with me
我找誰回憶我們的故事啊
if you are gone.
你還說呢
Hey, come on.
這兩年你都沒打給我
You didn't even try to contact me in the past two years.
你也沒打給我好不好
You didn't call either.
真敢講
How dare you mention it.
那妳最近都在幹嘛
So, what have you been doing lately?
沒幹嘛啊
Nothing much, really.
還不就上課唸書
Same old thing, studying.
那你呢
What about you?
你該不會常翹課吧
Still skipping classes?
當然啊
Of course
我本來就不喜歡唸書啊
I never liked studying anyway
我是為了妳才念的耶
I only studied because of you.
哇 說的這麼好聽
Wow! So sweet.
那天晚上 我們聊了很多回憶
We had a long chat that night, talking about the old days.
好多好多用功讀書 只為了更靠近她的日子
The old days when I tried everything to get closer to her.
那妳有男朋友了嗎
So, do you have a boyfriend now?
要你管啊
It's none of your business.
我
I...um...
後來跟阿和在一起過
I... was with A-Ho for a while
我知道啊
I know
我有聽他說
I heard.
但後來為什麼分手
Why did you guys split up?
我一直不想問他 想到就度爛
I didn't want to ask him cause that just made me want to kick his ass.
他對妳不好嗎
Was he mean to you?
也不是
Not really
我只是覺得 阿和不夠喜歡我
I just felt that he didn't like me that much.
阿和很喜歡妳
No, A-Ho was crazy about you, head over heels!
被你喜歡過 很難覺得別人有那麼喜歡我
Having being loved by you makes it harder for me to feel other's love.
哇 這麼感人啊
You are kidding me right?
你不要破壞氣氛喔現在
Don't ruin it now.
沈佳宜
Hey, Shen Chia-Yi.
我可不可以問妳
Can I ask you a question?
為什麼當時沒有想要和我在一起啊
Why didn't you want to be with me at that time?
常常聽到人家說啊
You know...
戀愛最美好的時候
People always say that the most wonderful time of a relationship
就是暖昧的時候
happens before it really happens.
等到真正在一起了
When two people are together.
很多感覺都會消失不見
The magic vanishes easily.
所以我就想 乾脆就讓你再追我久一點
So I thought it'd be better if I let you chase me longer.
不然等你追到我之後就變懶了 那我不是很虧嗎
Otherwise, if we got together right away, it'd be less fun.
妳真的很雞巴耶
Man, that's slack!
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳相信有平行時空嗎
Do you believe in parallel universe?
也許在那個平行時空裡 我們是在一起的
Maybe in that universe, we are together.
真羨慕他們啊
How I envy them.
謝謝你喜歡我
Thank you for liking me.
我也很喜歡
Yes.
當年喜歡妳的我
Thank you for letting me like you in those years.
妳永遠是我眼中的蘋果
You are always the apple of my eye.
大四了
Then it came to Senior year.
我身邊的每一個人都在準備考研究所
Everyone around me was preparing for grad schools
我不曉得我將來想做什麼
I had no idea what I wanted to do at that time.
可是每個人都在唸書 弄得我很緊張
Everyone was studying so hard and it made me nervous.
只好跟著大家一起跑圖書館
So I decided to join them in the library.
但莫名其妙的 我卻開始在網路上寫起了小說
And out of the blue, I started to write stories on my blog.
老曹退伍後沒去美國打NBA
Tsao didn't make his way to NBA.
反而跑去二手車廠賣車
He ended up selling second hand cars.
他是天生好手
And it turned out he's pretty good at it.
平均每兩天就可以賣出一台車
On average, he sells one car every other day.
嚇死人了
Unbelievable.
引擎聲 它騙不了人的
The engine never lies.
來
Here.
你的右腳輕踩一下油門
Put your foot on the gas gently.
是不是 還沒改喔
Hear that sound?
還沒改之前 它的聲線就已經非常的飽滿
It's this powerful before we upgrade it, can you imagine if we do?
當它上路之後 轉速到達兩千TURBO
I bet it is going to run over 2000 rpm when it hits the road.
馬力可說是隨傳隨到
The horsepower is beyond your imagination.
怎麼樣啊 喜歡吧
What do you think? You like it?
喜歡
I like it.
喜歡的話 我們上路開一段怎麼樣
Well then, how about we take this beast out for a ride?
好
Okay.
GO
該邊考上了公務員
Groin passed the government worker's exam.
在永和市立圖書館當行政課員
He is now working as a librarian.
每天都在騙無知的小美眉
Which he gets to play perform magic to young innocent girls every day.
同學 看清楚這本書 吹口氣吧
See this book? Blow on it.
看仔細喔
Now, pay attention.
你神經病啊
Are you nuts?
給我站住
Stop there.
阿和那個胖子在當保險業務
A-Ho became an insurance sales man.
很喜歡開車的他
He loves driving his car.
平均一天有十二個小時都待在車上 雖然有點狼狽
Every day he spends about 12 hours in it, even though it's tough
但他一定會成功的
I do believe he will succeed one day.
畢竟他可是我們之間唯一追到過沈佳宜的人啊
After all he is the only person who has officially dated Shen Chia-Yi.
喂 李先生嗎
Hello, is this Mr. Lee?
是是 我是
Yes, speaking.
對啊 就是上次跟您提過的那個壽險型保單喔
Hi, remember the insurance plan that I talked to you about last time?
我已經把資料都準備好了
I have already gathered all the information for you.
那是不是跟您約個時間到您公司去跟您做個詳細的說明
Just wondering when is a good time to pay you a visit in your office.
勃起大學畢業後先去當兵 然後立刻飛去美國念碩士
Boner flew to America for graduate school immediately after his military service.
勃起的英文很爛
Boner's English sucked
我真不知道他是哪來的勇氣去美國玩大冒險
I don't know how the hell he had the guts to go to the States.
大概真的很想換個國家打手槍吧
Perhaps he wanted to masturbate in a different country.
如果書念不會 就儘管回來 知道嗎
If you can't stand it, just come back, understand?
媽 妳不要亂講話啦
Ma, stop talking nonsense
媽媽是跟你說真的啦
I am serious.
你如果書念不好就回來
If it's too hard, then just come back
媽媽不會罵你啦
I will not blame you, I promise.
媽 我知道啦
Fine, I got it.
來跟爸爸說再見一下
Okay, it's dad's turn to say good-bye now.
勃起這一飛 兩年又過去了
Two years gone by while Boner was overseas.
對了 還有胡家瑋
Oh, yes, and there is Hu Chia-Wei.
那一個只會畫智障光頭的胡家瑋
That girl who always drew retarded stuff in her books.
現在有了另外一個名字
She now has another name.
彎彎
Wan Wan.
所以囉 最後會實現夢想的
So it proves that those who realize their dreams
往往不是最有才華的人
are often not the most clever ones in school.
而是直到最後 也絕不放棄的那一個人
But they are definitely those who persist till the end
我很高興 我看走眼了
I am very glad that I was wrong.
當勃起把外國學歷騙回台灣的時候
When Boner came home with a foreign degree
我接到了一通電話
I received a phone call.
喂
Hello.
喂 老朋友 在忙嗎
Hello, old friend, are you busy?
當然忙啊
Of course I am busy
不管 這件事第一個要告訴你
I don't care, there is something that I want you to be the first to know.
怎樣
What is it?
有空讓我再追妳一次啊
You got time for me to go after you again?
這次恐怕不行喔
Not this time, I am afraid.
為什麼
Why?
欸 快一點啦
Hurry up!
今天大日子耶
It's a big day today.
欸 你想讓新娘子等你一個人喔
You want to make the bride wait for you?
乾杯
Cheers.
後悔了吧
Regret it now?
當年我這麼好追 你們全都去追沈佳宜啦
I was so available back then, but you guys all went for Shen Chia-Yi.
那我現在追還來得及嗎
So does that mean I still have a chance?
你很爛耶
You suck!
其實啊
I got to tell you something
我以前沒有認真追過沈佳宜
I wasn't really serious about chasing after Shen Chia-Yi before.
為什麼
Why?
因為我看你們大家都追她
I just didn't want to miss out.
所以我才跟著追她的啊
Everyone went after her, so I did, too.
比起我啊
In comparison to me
我真的覺得你們很不要臉耶
I must say, you guys are shameless.
人家現在已經成為別人的新娘子了
She is the bride today, but none of you is the groom.
你們竟然還有臉來參加這個婚禮
How dare you guys show your faces at this wedding.
真的是有夠厚臉皮的
Shameless!
許博淳
Hsu Bo-Chun.
我聽你在喇叭
Kiss my ass.
喝酒啦
Just drink!
好歹我也曾經追到過好不好
Oh, please, I have dated her, haven't I?
那是詐胡啦
That was a scam.
對啊詐胡啦
Exactly, cheater!
對了 對了
Hey,
我們來打個賭
let's make a bet.
我們猜拳
Let's do paper, scissors stone.
最輸的那一個人
The loser
等一下要在新郎新娘進場的時候伸腳 把新郎絆倒
will have to trip the groom when they walk in later.
太突然了啦 超糗的
What the hell was that? It's embarrassing!
你們這樣很壞耶 一點都不懂得祝福
You guys are mean. Can't you just show some love to the couple?
你不懂啦
You won't understand.
如果你真的非常喜歡過一個女生 就會知道
If you really like a girl.
要真心祝福她跟別人永遠幸福快樂 根本是不可能的事
It is impossible to see her marry to another guy and still bless them.
對啊
That's right.
像我們這種背後放箭的 才叫做真愛
True love means someone should sneak up and stabs the groom in the back.
對 真愛
Correct.
絆死他
Trip him!
我錯了
But I am wrong.
原來 當你真的非常非常喜歡一個女孩
In fact, when you really like a girl, you'd be happy for her.
當她有人疼 有人愛
When you see her finding her Mr. Right.
你會真心真意的祝福她
You will want them to be together.
永遠幸福快樂
And to live happily ever after.
來 靠近一點喔
Come closer.
再一個 來喔
One more, ready
一二三 來
1, 2, 3, go.
好 OK
OK
恭喜 恭喜 新婚愉快
Congratulations, happy marriage.
快快快
Come, quickly
我要在沈佳宜旁邊
I want to stand next to Shen Chia-Yi.
我們要拍多一點
We should take more photos.
要拍美一點喔
How do I look? Get a pretty one for me.
好 來喔 來喔
All right. Here it comes.
準備好了
Ready.
來 一二三 來
Ok, one, two, three, go.
再一次喔 來喔來喔來喔 再一次喔 來
One more, one, two, three... done.
OK
謝謝
Thank you.
新郎大哥 打個商量
Hey, man, we have a suggestion.
什麼商量
About what?
我們紅包包這麼多
See, the thing is that we have loaded you with cash.
想親新娘 不知道可不可以耶
Don't you think we have the right to kiss the bride?
新娘說好 我就沒問題呀
Well, I am fine if she says fine.
好啊
Well, fine.
想親新娘可以
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
不過呢 等一下你們要怎樣親新娘
You can kiss the bride.
就要先怎麼親我
But you have to kiss me first.
這樣才公平啊
Kiss me the way you want to kiss her, so that's fair.
沒聽說過來賓要親新娘
Bullshit!
還要過關斬將的
What kind of rule is that?
對啊
Yeah, no way.
你這樣太小氣了啦
Don't be stingy.
這樣不對啦
That is not right.
那就沒辦法囉
Well then... sorry.
哈哈哈 你們打的如意算…
Ha, ha... Look at yourself, guys.
幹嘛啊
What?
昨天謝謝
Thank you for yesterday.
真的假的啦
Are you for real?
還愛心考卷咧
A quiz made out of love...
你錯很多耶
You made so many mistakes.
你回去沒看參考書就直接寫 對不對
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
沈佳宜
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳超正點的
You were so cool when you shouted at him.
哭起來也超正的
You look so pretty when you cry, too.
雖然我還沒追到妳
Even though we are not seeing each other yet.
不過 那些追都沒追過妳的男生
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼可以牽你的手
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我自己都沒牽過
I haven't even held them myself.
你特地辦個比賽 把自己搞受傷
You held this game and got yourself hurt.
你怎麼會這麼幼稚啊
How can you be so childish?
幼稚
Childish?
就是幼稚
Yes, childish.
很幼稚
Very childish and totally immature.
笨蛋
Idiot.
對啦 我就是笨蛋啦
Yes, I am an idiot.
大笨蛋
Moron.
大笨蛋才會追妳這麼久
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase you for such a long time.
你什麼都不懂
You don't understand anything.
我就是什麼都不懂啦
You're right, I don't!
對不起
Sorry
是我太幼稚了
I was the immature one.
其實會解這種題目有什麼了不起的
Being able to solve these tricky math questions does not help anything in life!
我敢跟妳賭
You want to bet?
十年後我連LOG是什麼都不知道
I won't even know what “log” means ten years later.
還是可以活得好好的
And it doesn't make my life any harder.
嗯
Emmmm.
妳不相信
You don't believe me
我相信啊
I do believe you.
相信還那麼用功讀書
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生本來就有很多事是徒勞無功的啊
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
你想知道答案嗎
Do you want to know the answer?
如果柯景騰跟我告白的話 我會很高興的
If Ko Ching-Teng comes and confesses to me I will be very happy.
沈 佳 宜
Shen Chia-Yi
我 喜 歡 妳
I like you very much.
(Ok, let's be together)
真羨慕他們呢
How I envy them.
謝謝你喜歡我
Thank you for liking me.
那我就繼續幼稚下去囉
Well then, I am just going to keep on acting childish.
一定要喔
Sure, why not!
(Happy Marriage, to the apple of my eye)
洋基耶
Hey, Yankees.
真的耶
Yeah!
阿建
A- Chian.
柯騰
Hey, Ko-Teng.
你有沒有想過把我們的故事寫成小說啊
Have you thought about writing our story?
早就想啦
Of course I did!
只是還想不到書名 不知道怎麼開頭
I just haven't come up a good name to start with.
我打手槍那件事可不可以不要寫
Hey, can you leave out the part which I was masturbating?
一定寫
Sorry man... that has to be in the story.
如果你真的要寫的話
If you really are going to write it.
記得把我寫帥一點啊
Don't forget to let your readers know how handsome I am.
順便幫我徵女友
By the way, can you put in some dating advertisements for me, too!
拜託 你不是要追彎彎
Come on, I thought you are going after Wan Wan?
都追啦
Haha, doesn't really matter.
This is the last image we shot before wrapping up shooting.
The director conspired with the make-up artist to prank the cast.
And painted Michelle Chen's face into...